<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Abhishek Singh</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2017-03-04T15:46:31+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Abhishek Singh</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Clickbait</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/10/03/clickbait/"/>
   <updated>2016-10-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/10/03/clickbait</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think clickbait is the reason many of us face information overload daily. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clickbait exists in more subtle ways than you can notice. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=5-O2n8FO6Is&quot;&gt;video like this&lt;/a&gt; is the clear version of it. It’s right there in front of you, and you know it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not everything is so in-your-face, though. Vague headlines where the content has little to no relation the headline itself are the norm these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t realise this because we’ve been familiarised with it over the years. Such occurrences are so common that we’ve adapted to see them as normal. This is disadvantageous on many levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our brain can only handle so much information at a time. Moreover, when you’re trying to juggle so many events that your brain can’t choose which is important enough to remember, it goes the easy route; it picks the most interesting thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s why. If you study calculus (all hail calculus) and then watch someone like Pewdiepie, you’re more likely to remember the latter, albeit, in the short term, which means that over time you’ll forget the video faster than you’ll forget how to integrate. But regarding strictly one-time occurrences, the more rich experiences come out on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a solution to this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably not. It’s almost impossible that anybody’s going to convince anybody to use clear titles and thumbnails. So there’s one thing left, and most people can’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-control. You are the things you consume, and that includes everything on the internet. The more careful you are in what you watch, read and listen to, the better it is for your brain and society in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anybody can do it, not everyone in the years to come will choose to or will be able to do it. This is why deep working individuals are required more than ever before. The concept of ‘average’ was over years ago, and today the best of the best flourish and a big part of that the focus on essential consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information is power. But there are two kinds, and most of us seem to choose the worse kind every time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Clocks</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/14/clocks/"/>
   <updated>2016-09-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/14/clocks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tick tock, tick tock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin got up from his chair, keeping the book aside. It was time for sleep. He checked the clock; it was 1:43 AM. No time to be awake. He turned the lamp off, and entered the bed, closing his eyes, losing his consciousness slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tick tock, tick tock, tick tock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sound of the clock was interrupting him. He hadn’t noticed it till now, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;’For the sake of sleep, shut the hell up.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tick tock, tick…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;￼He realised clocks didn’t turn themselves off, apparently. Why couldn’t there be voice controlled clocks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘I would buy one if they just MADE IT!’ He shouted to his conscious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing. It was still going. Looks like no matter what, the clock wasn’t going to listen to him. He’d have to get up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Hsjsajad’, he mumbled random letters as he got up. Probably his way to curse. He pressed the ‘snooze’ button. No shit, it was going. It was still going. He pressed it harder, he pressed it a thousand times. Bet he broke the world record for the most snoozing in a minute. And it kept going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘This thing is determined’ he thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin couldn’t sleep like this. He moved towards the sofa to sleep. He lay there, closing his eyes, losing his consciousness slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again. Tick tock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Now WHAT? Can’t a gentleman sleep or what! DAMN YOU!’ So much for being a gentleman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was too much. Kevin got up in rage, checking all around him the origin of the sound so he could thrash the thing that was doing this with a hammer, so it dare not make such a sound again. No sign, the room was void of any clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the clock in the room had stopped, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where was this sound coming from then? Kevin moved to check the area around the sofa, looking at every corner. Nothing, this was a dark, clock free space of cheap Ikea furniture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sound was coming from somewhere, but Kevin couldn’t figure it out. It was impossible to sleep in such sound, even if he stuffed sound proof glass in his ears. He moved a bit around the house. Not in search of anything, but for a seemingly quieter place where this sound could not reach. The house was small, so it was hard to find a place where this horrible thing wouldn’t pierce his mind. Horrible it was, it was a monster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Upstairs maybe’, he thought. Maybe there he’d find tranquillity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He walked upstairs. The sound of the clock was faint now, but he could still hear it. He moved to enter the only room which was upstairs; maybe it couldn’t penetrate the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tick tock, tick tock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It became louder! This was getting harder to figure out at the moment. Where was this sound coming from? Kevin was pretty sure that there was no clock at all on the upper floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, how? He was utterly confused. A puzzled expression covered his face. He looked out the window of the second floor. The neighbourhood was a ghost town. Not a soul was to be found roaming around. A soft breeze was blowing, as was evident from the leaves of the flying around aimlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘At least they get to enjoy quiet’, he thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something turned his attention back to the house. The sound had just become even louder, with still whatsoever no direction where it was coming from. It seemed to vibrate through all the walls. It was everywhere, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was getting unbearable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tick tock, tick tock, tick tock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin was scared. It was evident this was nothing of this universe. Where else did clocks would you find so monstrous? The thing was made to ‘wake you up’, not to ‘keep you up.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time, clock, the sound; these were eating him alive. He darted downstairs. Bet he broke the world record for the fastest time to descend stairs too. He was at the door in an instant, and he turned the knob. One more second and he would die of this sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He didn’t. But the door didn’t open. It was locked, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had an idea; a light shone in his mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘I am saved!’ exclaimed he.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He rushed towards the phone. He picked it up and put it to his ear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tick tock, tick tock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was coming through the speaker of the phone also, apparently. Brilliant, his last attempt at redemption and this is what he gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this moment, just as the clock chimed off the hour, horror and serenity merged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin sat down and kept quiet. The sound of clocks continued to reverberate. They buzzed, they chimed, they rang. But his mind was empty. His voice was empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, the world was empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He opened his eyes. He was in his bed; it was 7. Birds were chirping and light reflected throughout the room. The clock was buzzing uncontrollably, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tick tock, tick tock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he pressed snooze. It became quiet again. Kevin went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>December Cold</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/07/december-cold/"/>
   <updated>2016-09-07T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/07/december-cold</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was a cold morning. Rain fell ever so slightly outside as I sipped hot chocolate. The warm, sweet aroma touched my lips like a drink from the heavens itself. I wrapped the blanket around me tighter as a slight breeze blew in from the balcony.  It was a Sunday, a day off from work and I was enjoying it the best I could. Mornings seldom got any bett…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Rohan beta, come down for a bit, would you?” came the shout of some sort of devil from below. It was my neighbour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat there frozen, unable to move, or maybe I just didn’t want to. All kind of wrong thoughts flew straight through my mind. I didn’t reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are you there or not?” she rang back. I wouldn’t have been, but if she told my mother about it, I was going to get a severe scolding. After everything, I had to get up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put my cup down and took the blanket off. A chill went right through my body. I had to cover myself with the blanket again to stop shivering. Anyhow, I managed to walk down and get to her gate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There she was, wrapped in a blanket herself, drinking tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Would you go and get some grocery, my dearie?” I would have run away that very moment, but she was old, and I didn’t want her to feel bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where’s your son?” I inquired with as much care as I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s out for work somewhere”. At that moment I realised that he must be out drunk with his friends, partying somewhere. I ceased to think of any further questions plaguing my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After taking the money from her, I started the walk towards the long, dreadful journey that lay ahead of me. Even with the blanket on, it was freezing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I wonder why isn’t it snowing already”. I thought to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way was empty, void of anyone whatsoever. This struck me awkwardly at first, but then I realised that I must be the only one dumb enough to come out in this cold to buy groceries. I wonder why I hadn’t asked her why she needed some grocery so urgently in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must have reached the store in about a year or so. The shopkeeper was inside, and I had to shout at the top of my lungs to get him out. At that moment, shouting meant whimpering like a child as best I could. Thankfully, he listened. He came out rubbing his hands together wearing a monkey cap, evidently feeling the cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sire, what do you want? It’s so cold.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read him the list, and he slowly gave me the things I wanted albeit with some unhappiness. After paying him, I resumed my journey back to my ultimate goal, my bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back, I was startled to see a man out in the cold. He was the only soul I had seen on my way, and he was shivering uncontrollably. He sat on the footpath, hands and legs cramped and he was breathing heavily. He must have been around 60 and was trying to sell, or rather do something, anything, with his newspapers and magazines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curious, I approached the man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Haan bhaiya, what are you doing here in this cold? The road’s empty; you can’t be selling anything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, in fact, I am. In the life of someone like me, this is what I have to do to survive.” he could barely get the words out of his mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt sorry for him. Instinctively, I brought three newspapers and two magazines. He was utterly thankful. Just as I was starting back, I remembered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Here, have this blanket,” I said as I handed it over to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?” he said, startled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, you can have it,” I replied with a smile on my face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took it and immediately hugged me. I felt awkward, to say the least, but I hugged him back and then started on my journey back. Surprisingly, I didn’t feel cold at all. I still wonder where that could have gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached back and handed her over the goods and went back up. The hot chocolate had gone cold. I sat back on my bed, reminiscing on my encounter with the old man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning had been quite warm after all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Day the Metro Stood Still</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/05/09/the-day-the-metro-stood-still/"/>
   <updated>2016-05-09T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/09/the-day-the-metro-stood-still</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For a while, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around 6:30 PM when I reached the station. The day seemed to be coming down slowly as I heaved my backpack through the security checkpoint, up the stairs and into the metro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no seats being available, (which is the usual case) I stood leaning on the glass that bordered a row of seats, near the door. Soon enough, the voice chimed, and the doors went shut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the metro didn’t move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happened sometimes, and thus I just stood there staring blankly into the void. After a while, I felt hungry, and so I took out my way-past-lunch box and started eating, an activity I would have loved to do while being seated, but fate didn’t approve of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minutes passed. Till then, people had tried to gently knock open the metro door, as if they were trying to enter someone’s home, a weird couple had smiled at me for a minute while I was eating and I’d finished the monotonous activity of chewing all my meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, I waited. A whole 15 minutes must have passed when finally the metro moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It went on for some time, with people cramming in like none of their business. It was a Wednesday, around 7 PM. I should have known better. I went on looking over people’s shoulders trying to find out which secret they were trying to text their buddies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The metro came to a halt again at Mayur Vihar, where it stood again for around 10 minutes before moving. Nobody significant entered or exited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It stopped again. This time not at a station, but just around 100 metres before Yamuna Bank. I was getting fed up, but the other option was complaining out loud about how the metro sucks and how we should press the ‘emergency’ button and talk to the driver like other people in my compartment were doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stuck to being silent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the metro moved again and reached the Yamuna Bank metro station in what seemed like an eternity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After repeating customary lines like - “Ma’am, could you please get aside?” or “Excuse me, sir.”, I finally got out of the metro and went to the other platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I noticed was a big ruckus. Also, people taking selfies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evidently, a metro hadn’t arrived to go to Vaishali for such a long time that a herd of people had assembled at the place. Every time a horn blared, the people whistled and chanted only to discover that the metro arriving wasn’t the one they were waiting for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people just gave up and sat beside the stairs in the hope that a metro might come. Others teetered on the edge of the platform to look for any sign of lights approaching from the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there were the people who raised their phones up through the crowd. Some were looking at their video camera to catch a glimpse of the metro; others were just taking a selfie. What in god’s name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me? I stood there without a single shred of hope that I was getting home anytime soon. Even if a metro did arrive, the already overflowing metro wouldn’t have accommodated 1% of the herd standing there, and I wasn’t going to be a part of that 1%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, I called up my father to get me out of there and thus began my journey to reach the extraction point. Just to get out well and alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved down and straight with a sea of people also attempting to exit the station. You didn’t need to move at all, actually. The people pushing from behind carried you with them. I went along the tide. It moved slowly and painfully. I finally managed to reach the top, only to discover that the rate of people exiting vs. the people coming in was highly disproportionate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody pushed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the authorities gave in, and the door was forced open. Nobody was to swipe their card, a benefit for the metro service as they could now take quite an amount of penalty money from us. I did hear some women shouting from behind me, but at the moment couldn’t figure out whether it was directed at me or someone else. I continued pushing, and everyone came out to a dreary night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started walking immediately because that’s what everyone else seemed to be doing at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than a thousand people walked on the left side of the road that went out of the Yamuna Bank station. Nobody had discussed this amongst each other, but there seemed to be a silent truce that vehicles on the right, people on the left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I broke off the crowd for a moment and looked in the distance. I was at a religious tourist attraction where a line of people was moving along to get a glimpse of their God. For the moment, that God never seemed to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People were still taking selfies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed a few individuals disappearing under what seemed to be the tracks. There was a huge crowd gathered round, and when I tried to look down, I was met with thorns from a bush. I suffered thorns in my arm trying to fend off the enemy. A person warned me that thorns were dangerous foes and I thought it better to move along further down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few more minutes of walking, I finally saw my destination. I was sweating like I had just run a marathon and carrying the heavy backpack had been a nightmare, but there was the brightly lit main road. Now, just the wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thirsty when I finally did reach and looked around if I could find water or a soft drink anywhere. There, I found a small stall managed by a senior man. He looked fed up of the crowd that was demanding stuff from him but obliged anyway. This was probably his most successful night after all. My attempts were unsuccessful, though, as water seemed to have run out and he was busier giving people Marlboro and Captain than giving me anything to drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left and stood there, looking at the long line of cars that blocked the road and wondered how long it would take for dad to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first good news of the day, he came soon enough. I sat in the extraction vehicle, a Chevrolet Sail (the best in class) and we took off. There I noticed how far people had come from the station. They were probably going to walk home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I don’t know. I was in the car, and a tiring journey was now over. I felt momentary pity for them as I leaned back and dozed off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is an exaggerated account of the 8th July 2015 minor metro snag that occurred when a metro stopped due to a problem in the electrical lines.)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Revolution</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/02/19/the-revolution/"/>
   <updated>2016-02-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/02/19/the-revolution</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We were the oppressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thrown by the society, a mere fragment of broken glass shattered by the hopeless world. In a mere blink of the eyes, we vanished, torn and undone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were the outlaws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mocked, frowned upon. We were the creators of destruction, the facilitators of glory. For in us rested the future, and in us, we faced the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were the stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some were with us, then by definition, others against us. And what is life, without enemies to face together with friends?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For we were the oppressed, the outlaws and the stars. And without us, this nation would never be the same. And for that very same reason, we rose. Rose for the truth, for the lie and for those who were with us and against us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were no sides, but a crusade against time and what was right. And in the end, all that mattered was a dauntless and ceaseless light, for that guided us to oblivion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why we are the revolutionaries. Mere mortals in the face of God, we struck back. We were violent in peace, loud in silence and full in an empty void.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live on today, in memories, in truth and in the lives of the billions of people who remember us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if we may be forgotten some day, the revolution will live on. Today, tomorrow and eternally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For we are the eternal, the incessant and the infinite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we, are forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello, World!</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/hello-world/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/hello-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name’s Abhishek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t know what else to say for my first post so, hello, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
